Contact

+923331904163 (Work) adilsher973@gmail.com

www.linkedin.com/in/adilsher (LinkedIn)

Top Skills

Laravel

Terraform

Amazon Web Services (AWS)

Certifications

Information Technology Training Summit

One Day Training Session on Brand Management

Al For Everyone

43rd Training Course on Change in Behavior

Microsoft Office Specialist Word 2013

Adil Sher

Team Lead at Business Partner Group Australia | App Developer | Thought Leader | Strategist

Islāmābād, Pakistan

Summary

I talk business sense through effective communication and strategic thinking backed up with ability to conduct research, leadership and decision making skills. Responsible for employing tech talent and developing company's strategy for using tech resources.

Experience

Business Partner Group
11 months

Information Technology Team Lead September 2022 - Present (5 months)

Brisbane, Queensland, Australia

- Help with hiring the team and provide team leadership.
- Contributing to the growth of the company through a successful team.
- Managing the day-to-day activities of the team.
- Cater to internal stakeholders and build the required applications.
- Conduct team meetings via Skype.
- Listen to team members' feedback and resolve any issues or conflicts.
- Encourage creativity and risk-taking.
- · Discover training needs and provide coaching.

Full Stack Developer March 2022 - Present (11 months)

Brisbane, Queensland, Australia

X3 Technologies Chief Technology Officer March 2022 - Present (11 months)

Islāmābād, Pakistan

I talk business sense through effective communication and strategic thinking backed up with ability to conduct research, leadership and decision making skills. Responsible for employing tech talent and developing company's strategy for using tech resources.

Freelance

Application Developer

December 2018 - Present (4 years 2 months)

NorthBay Solutions

Trainee

October 2022 - December 2022 (3 months)

Islāmābād, Pakistan

AWS Certified Solutions Architect Associate.

This Bootcamp was divided into 10 weeks. I learned about various AWS Services and performed hands on labs under expert supervision.

Wing Sols

11 months

Project Manager

May 2021 - March 2022 (11 months)

Islāmābād, Pakistan

- Coordinating with cross-discipline team members to make sure that all parties are on track with project requirements, deadlines, and schedules.
- Meeting with project team members to identify and resolve issues.
- Submitting project deliverables and ensuring that they adhere to quality standards.
- Preparing status reports by gathering, analyzing, and summarizing relevant information.
- Establishing effective project communication plans and ensuring their execution.
- Facilitating change requests to ensure that all parties are informed of the impacts on schedule and budget.
- Coordinating the development of user manuals, training materials, and other documents as needed to enable successful implementation and turnover of the process or system to the clients.
- Identifying and developing new opportunities with clients.
- Obtaining customer acceptance of project deliverables.
- Managing customer satisfaction within the project transition period.
- Conducting post-project evaluation and identifying successful and unsuccessful project elements.
- ERP project oversight.

Information Technology Team Lead

May 2021 - March 2022 (11 months)

Islāmābād, Pakistan

- Managing the day-to-day activities of the team.
- Motivating the team to achieve organizational goals.
- Developing and implementing a timeline to achieve targets.
- Delegating tasks to team members.
- Conducting training of team members to maximize their potential.
- · Conducting quarterly performance reviews.
- Contributing to the growth of the company through a successful team.
- Creating a pleasant working environment that inspires the team.
- Empowering team members with skills to improve their confidence, product knowledge, and communication skills.

Bid Specialist

May 2021 - March 2022 (11 months)

Islāmābād, Pakistan

- Working under the supervision of the Bid Coordinator and assisting them in developing the proposal structure.
- Reviewing and editing previously written content where necessary.
- Working with other team members to produce written bid responses and presentation collateral in line with deadlines.
- Writing content for use in the bid for Upwork, communicating with the clients.
- Preparing presentations and all supporting documentation, ensuring a cohesive and consistent approach.

x7remes

Android Developer

December 2020 - March 2021 (4 months)

Islāmābād, Pakistan

- Performing software development for Android based Language Learning system using Java, Android application Framework Architecture, Material Design and APIs.
- Work with API developers to provide data to the apps via RESTful APIs w/ JSON.
- Work with the Manager of Mobile Development to provide estimates and status updates.
- Use of Frame Layout, Linear Layout, and Relative Layout in Android Studio for responsive screen designs.
- Carry out quality assurance tests to discover errors and optimize usability.

Panacloud

Trainee

May 2020 - October 2020 (6 months)

Islāmābād, Pakistan

I was a part of an online bootcamp. It was mainly focused on learning to build Modern Full Stack Serverless Mobile Web Apps and Websites including e-commerce apps using React, Gatsby.js, Redux, GraphQL, RESTful OpenAPI, Serverless, AWS Lambda Functions, AWS Lambda Containers, AWS Aruora Serverless, AWS Neptune, AWS EventBridge, MongoDB, FaunaDB, Git, GitHub, GitHub Actions, Netlify, Contentful, Stripe, SnipCart, Shopify, etc.

Link to Bootcamp: https://panacloud.github.io/bootcamp-2020/? fbclid=IwAR2qqFN5IFzERJ0mYZXUZWA6KjKh_adpUieVIhjRvrQvhr5wTid9ywCGKI

Link to my developed projects:

https://expense-tracker-by-adilsher.surge.sh/

http://animations4b-adilsher.surge.sh/

https://animation4a-adilsher.surge.sh/

https://shoe-store-adilsher.surge.sh/

https://covid19-tracker-adilsher.surge.sh/

Virtual University of Pakistan
Front Desk Officer
August 2019 - October 2020 (1 year 3 months)

Islāmābād, Pakistan

I worked as a Front Desk Officer at Virtual University of Pakistan for the time of admissions during my degree.

I was mainly responsible for guiding guests about the admissions guidelines. Other duties included greeting guests, taking phone calls, sorting correspondence, answering to visitors inquiries, maintaining the reception area clean and organized, receiving shipments, updating records and files, and maintaining schedules.

Quaidsol

Intern

May 2019 - July 2019 (3 months)

Rawalpindi, Punjab, Pakistan

I worked as an Intern at the company to improve my Web Development skills for 3 months.

I got hands on experience in learning to use PHP and MySQLi. I also got my hands on Android Studio and used its Frame Layout to deploy my web app in mobile phone as its app. I completed my FYP with the help of this internship.

Later, this opportunity helped me to develop a similar app for a local client.

Cognition Hub

Intern

November 2018 - January 2019 (3 months)

Islāmābād, Pakistan

I worked as an intern at Cognition Hub for six weeks.

I got hands on practice in learning to use HTML, CSS, BOOTSTRAP, JQUERY and AJAX for Web Development.

Education

Virtual University of Pakistan

Bachelor of Science - BS, Computer Software Engineering · (2014 - 2020)